<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kush1729.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://kush1729.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-07-12T21:13:40+00:00</updated><id>https://kush1729.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kush Singhal’s Website</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Arithmetic Theory of Quadratic Forms</title><link href="https://kush1729.github.io/teaching/2023/summer-quadratic_forms/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Arithmetic Theory of Quadratic Forms" /><published>2023-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kush1729.github.io/teaching/2023/summer-quadratic_forms</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kush1729.github.io/teaching/2023/summer-quadratic_forms/"><![CDATA[<p>In this tutorial, we will study the arithmetic theory of quadratic forms in a down-to-earth and self-contained manner. Secretly, this tutorial is meant to be an introduction to some of the techniques of modern number theory. The hope is to show what algebraic number theory looks like outside of the typical undergraduate course.</p>

<p>This tutorial is roughly split into two parts. For the first part, we will look at the classification problem of quadratic forms over number fields, p-adic fields, and their rings of integers. The big theorems that we will prove (from scratch) are the Hasse-Minkowski theorem (an instance of the very general local-to-global philosophy pervading all of modern number theory), and the full classification of arithmetic lattices. For the second part, we will build up to a statement of the Siegel-Weil mass formula and its applications. For the most part, we will be solely working over \(\mathbb{Q}\) and its quadratic extensions.</p>

<p>For more detail, as well as for prerequisites, other summer tutorials at Harvard, and requirements for the tutorial, check <a href="https://www.math.harvard.edu/undergraduate/the-2023-summer-tutorial-program/">this</a> out.</p>

<h2 id="course-notes">Course Notes</h2>

<p>I will be writing my own course notes, which I will make available <a href="https://kush1729.github.io/assets/pdf/Quadratic_Forms_Lecture_Notes.pdf">here</a>.</p>

<p>There will also be weekly problem sets, which are NOT required. The problem sets are just exercises for those who are interested in becoming more comfortable with the topic. Problem Sets: <a href="https://kush1729.github.io/assets/pdf/PSet1-Sum23QF.pdf">1</a>, <a href="https://kush1729.github.io/assets/pdf/PSet2-Sum23QF.pdf">2</a></p>

<p>Here’s a (non-exhaustive) list of possible final presentation/report topics, in no particular order: (1) structure theory for orthogonal groups; (2) quadratic forms over function fields; (3) computational aspects of lattices; (4) applications of lattice theory (sphere packing, error correcting codes, etc); (5) unimodular lattices over the integers; (6) generalization to lattice cosets; (7) spin groups; (8) quadratic forms over ramified dyadic local fields; (9) relationship between class field theory and quadratic space theory.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a summer tutorial that I am going to run on the arithmetic theory of quadratic forms.]]></summary></entry></feed>